in inkscape 1.3 there are new on canvas
在Inkscape 1.3中，画布上有新功能
blur controls
模糊控制
let's make a logo using directional blur
让我们使用方向模糊来制作一个徽标
I will create a black background then I
我将创建一个黑色背景，然后我
select the text tool and click on the
选择文本工具，然后单击
canvas I will use Montserrat extra bold
画布I将使用蒙特塞拉特格外粗体
which is a free Google font I type
这是我输入的免费谷歌字体
inkscape
墨迹
for the text I will have no fill but
对于文本，我将没有填充物，但
only a stroke I want to have a gradient
只有一个笔划，我想有一个渐变
inside the stroke I open fill and stroke
在笔触内部，我打开填充和笔触
and stroke paint I click on linear
和笔画，我点击了线性
gradient
渐变
I want my gradient to have four colors I
我希望我的渐变有四种颜色
imported a screenshot of the colors I
导入了I颜色的屏幕截图
used
使用
I will sample them with a dropper tool
我会用滴管工具把它们取出来
for the left color stop I hold shift and
对于左侧的色标，我按住Shift键并
click on the Green
点击绿色
and for the right color stop I hold
为了合适的颜色，我拿着
shift and click on the yellow
按住Shift键并单击黄色
now I will create two extra color stops
现在，我将创建两个额外的颜色色标
I can do this by double clicking on the
我可以通过双击
gradient
渐变
and I can drag the color stops or
我可以拖动色标或
position them numerically
用数字表示它们的位置
I make the second color stop blue and
我让第二种颜色停止为蓝色
the third color stop I make magenta now
我现在做洋红的第三个色标
let's give the text the directional blur
让我们将文本设置为方向模糊
for the blur I will duplicate the text
对于模糊，我将复制文本
I go to fill and stroke and stroke paint
我去填画，画画，画画
I set blur to 30.
我将模糊设置为30。
I only want the blur to be horizontal so
我只希望模糊是水平的，所以
I select the node tool I will remove the
我选择节点工具，我将删除
vertical blur Direction
垂直模糊方向
and I will reduce the opacity to 50
我会把不透明度降低到50
percent
百分比
I call the path blur
我称这条路为模糊
now let's give the text some accent
现在让我们给这篇课文加上一些重音
light I duplicate the text and call it
轻我复制文本并将其命名为
accent I make the stroke white and
口音：我把笔触写成白色
reduce the stroke width I want the white
减少笔触宽度我想要白色
accent to fade out to the bottom to do
口音要淡出到底部去做
this I will apply a mask
这个我会贴上一个面膜
I drag a rectangle over the text which
我在文本上拖出一个矩形，
will become the mask
将成为面具
in a mask white reveals and black
在面具中，白色和黑色显露出来
conceals so I will give the rectangle a
隐藏，所以我将给矩形一个
gradient from white to black I go to
从白色到黑色的渐变我要去
fill and stroke and click on fill I
填充和描边，然后单击填充I
click on linear gradient
单击线性渐变
I position the gradient vertically the
我将渐变垂直放置在
bottom has to hide so I make it black
底部必须隐藏起来，所以我把它变成黑色
and the top has to be visible so I make
顶端必须是可见的，所以我要
it white I cannot actually see how the
它是白色的，我真的看不出
end result will look like
最终结果将如下所示
to easily tweak the actual result I will
为了轻松调整实际结果，我将
clone the rectangle
克隆矩形
in my layers I select the Clone in the
在我的层中，我在
accent text
带重音文本
I right click and choose set mask I can
我右击并选择Set MASK I Can
now adjust the gradient and see the
现在调整渐变并查看
result it has on the accent text
它在重音文本上产生的结果
I place the original on the bottom
我把原件放在底部
I will place the Mast accent in a group
我会把Mast口音放在一个小组里
to make the effect stronger I will make
为了让效果更强，我会让
some copies
一些副本
finally I will make a colored background
最后我会做一个彩色的背景
I will use the same colors I used for
我会用我以前用过的颜色
the text
文本
I duplicate the background I go to fill
我复制了我要填充的背景
and stroke and click on fill
和笔划，然后单击填充
I will reuse the gradient that I made
我将重复使用我制作的渐变
for the text
对于正文
behind gradient I open the menu and
在渐变后面，我打开菜单，
click on the gradient
单击渐变
I can get the gradient a name
我可以给渐变取一个名字
I will use a mask to fade out the
我会用一个面具来淡出
gradient
渐变
I drag an ellipse and make it white
我拖出一个椭圆形并将其变为白色
to be able to tweak the result I will
为了能够调整结果，我将
make a clone
克隆一个人
I blur the original
我模糊了原来的
I place the original on the bottom
我把原件放在底部
I select the Clone and shift-click on
我选择克隆并按住Shift并单击
the gradient to select them both
用于同时选择它们的渐变
I right click and choose set mask
我右击并选择设置蒙版
I position the gradient
我确定渐变的位置
and place the gradient below the text
并将渐变放置在文本下方
and I lower its opacity
我降低了它的不透明度
by adjusting the original mask I can
通过调整原始蒙版，我可以
adjust the result
调整结果